Weird is relative.
The Addams Family is a comedy, fantasy film directed by Barry Sonnenfeld.
When a man claiming to be long-lost Uncle Fester reappears after 25 years
lost, the family plans a celebration to wake the dead.
But the kids barely have time to warm up the electric chair before Morticia begins to
suspect Fester is fraud when he can't recall any of the details of Fester's life.
Gomez Addams, played by Raúl Juliá.
Morticia Addams, played by Anjelica Huston.
Uncle Fester, played by Christopher Lloyd.
Wednesday Addams, played by Christina Ricci.
Lurch, played by Carel Struycken.
Tully Alford, played by Dan Hedaya.
The Addams Family is a 1991 American supernatural black comedy film based
on the comic strip characters created by Charles Addams.
Directed by former cinematographer Barry Sonnenfeld in his feature directorial debut, the film stars Anjelica Huston, who was nominated for
a Golden Globe for her performance as Morticia Addams, Raul Julia as Gomez Addams, and Christopher Lloyd as Fester Addams.
The film focuses on a bizarre, macabre, aristocratic family who reconnect with someone
whom they believe to be a long-lost relative, Gomez's brother Fester Addams.
The film was noted for its turbulent production.
Originally developed at Orion Pictures, the film went $5 million over budget due to constant rewrites throughout shooting; health problems
of people involved in the filming; and an overall stressful filming for Sonnenfeld himself, which caused multiple delays.
The rise in production costs from the film's $25 million budget to $30 million led Orion, financially struggling and fearful of another
big-budget flop, to sell the film to Paramount Pictures, who completed the film and handled the film's domestic distribution.
Orion distributed the film internationally through Columbia Tri-Star Films.
The film was commercially successful, making back
almost seven times its production costs.
A sequel, Addams Family Values, was released in 1993.
The film explores themes of dancing, dead wish,
secret passage, fencing, black humor.
The tone is lighthearted.